<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep learning | BUPT-PRIS-727</title>
    <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/media/icon_huf3e0a2e529153e638e98ead8993d51a7_215518_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep learning</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention based Long Short-Term Memory Network for Coastal Visibility Forecast</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/attention-based-long-short-term-memory-network-for-coastal-visibility-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/attention-based-long-short-term-memory-network-for-coastal-visibility-forecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visibility prediction in coastal areas has always been an important issue affecting the safety of residents and the efficiency of urban transportation. The visibility prediction methods currently used by meteorological centers are mainly based on the statistical forecast with relatively low prediction accuracy and high computational complexity. These methods cannot work well with large amounts of data. However, with the rapid development of deep learning technology, the use of deep learning has become a primary trend. In this paper, we propose our visibility prediction model based on (Long Short-Term Memory) LSTM network and self-attention mechanism. The model takes Medium-range Forecasts Data from European Centre for Mediumrange Weather Forecasting (ECMWF) which we use EC data to refer it for simplicity and observatory visibility data as input to predict and uses the LSTM network as the backbone to extract time series information. We also use self-attention mechanism to process the input data before the data is input to the model to let the model better focus on the valuable information for prediction. Compared with the predicted visibility in EC data, our proposed method improved the 3-hour prediction accuracy by 20%, 1.5 times, and 8 times for high-range, medium-range, and low-range visibility, respectively. We also find the data imbalance will greatly affect the prediction accuracy for low-visibility data and use the weighted-loss and mix-up data augmentation strategy model in our model training. We improved the accuracy of low-visibility data by 1.2 times while the prediction results of high-visibility and medium-visibility data remained almost the same. In addition, we conduct several experiments to verify the effectiveness of our model design and the rationality of data augmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify, Guess and Reconstruct- Three Principles for Cloud Removal Task</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/identify-guess-and-reconstruct-three-principles-for-cloud-removal-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/identify-guess-and-reconstruct-three-principles-for-cloud-removal-task/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote sensing images serve a significant role in earth observation to tackle climate change and post-disaster reconstruction concerns. However, optical images are obscured by clouds or haze, preventing precise earth observation; hence, cloud removal has been a hot topic among concerned scholars. The objective of this article is to make cloud removal more efficient and explicable by proposing three principles: identifying clouds, guessing objects beneath the clouds, and reconstructing the cloudy area. In addition, a modified dual contrastive learning Generative Adversarial Network is proposed based on these three principles by adding cloud detection and weight sharing strategy to obtain cloud semantics. In particular, we align two datasets by forming a quaternary sample pair that includes not only optical pictures and SAR images, but also region information for a more precise reconstruction. Our experiment results on the integrated dataset reveal the superiority of proposed method over previous cloud removal methods and the effectiveness of added modules through ablation experiments, with PSNR and SSIM values of 26.2 and 0.728, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eyes of the Gods: A Survey of Unsupervised Domain Adaptation Methods Based on Remote Sensing Data</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/the-eyes-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/the-eyes-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of the remote sensing monitoring and computer vision technology, the deep learning method has made a great progress to achieve applications such as earth observation, climate change and even space exploration. However, the model trained on existing data cannot be directly used to handle the new remote sensing data, and labeling the new data is also time-consuming and labor-intensive. Unsupervised Domain Adaptation (UDA) is one of the solutions to the aforementioned problems of labeled data defined as the source domain and unlabeled data as the target domain, i.e., its essential purpose is to obtain a well-trained model and tackle the problem of data distribution discrepancy defined as the domain shift between the source and target domain. There are a lot of reviews that have elaborated on UDA methods based on natural data, but few of these studies take into consideration thorough remote sensing applications and contributions. Thus, in this paper, in order to explore the further progress and development of UDA methods in remote sensing, based on the analysis of the causes of domain shift, a comprehensive review is provided with a fine-grained taxonomy of UDA methods applied for remote sensing data, which includes Generative training, Adversarial training, Self-training and Hybrid training methods, to better assist scholars in understanding remote sensing data and further advance the development of methods. Moreover, remote sensing applications are introduced by a thorough dataset analysis. Meanwhile, we sort out definitions and methodology introductions of partial, open-set and multi-domain UDA, which are more pertinent to real-world remote sensing applications. We can draw the conclusion that UDA methods in the field of remote sensing data are carried out later than those applied in natural images, and due to the domain gap caused by appearance differences, most of methods focus on how to use generative training (GT) methods to improve the model’s performance. Finally, we describe the potential deficiencies and further in-depth insights of UDA in the field of remote sensing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Adaptation on Multiple Cloud Recognition From Different Types of Meteorological Satellite</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/domain-adaptation-on-multiple-cloud-recognition-from-different-types-of-meteorological-satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/domain-adaptation-on-multiple-cloud-recognition-from-different-types-of-meteorological-satellite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meteorological satellites have become an indispensable meteorological tool for earth observation, as aiding in areas such as cloud detection, which has important guiding significance for maritime activities. However, it is time-consuming and labor-intensive to obtain fine-grained annotations provided by artificial experience or mature satellite cloud products for multi-spectral maritime cloud imageries, especially when new satellites are launched. Moreover, due to the data discrepancy caused by different detection bands, existing models have inadequate generalization performance compared to new satellites, and some cannot be directly migrated. In this paper, to reduce the data distribution’s discrepancy, an approach is presented based on unsupervised domain adaption method for marine cloud detection task based on Himawari-8 satellite data as a source domain and Fengyun-4 satellite data as a target domain. The goal of the proposed method is to leverage the representation power of adversarial learning to extract domain-invariant features, consisting of a segmentation model, a feature extract model for target domain, and a domain discriminator. In addition, aiming to remedy the discrepancy of detection bands, a band mapping module is designed to implement consistency between different bands. The result of the experiments demonstrated the effectiveness of the proposed method with a 7% improvement compared with the comparative experiment. We also designed a series of statistical experiments on different satellite data to further study cloudy perception representation, including data visualization experiment and cloud type statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea fog detection based on unsupervised domain adaptation</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/sea-fog-detection-based-on-unsupervised-domain-adaptation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/sea-fog-detection-based-on-unsupervised-domain-adaptation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sea fog detection with remote sensing images is a challenging task. Driven by the different image characteristics between fog and other types of clouds, such as textures and colors, it can be achieved by using image processing methods. Currently, most of the available methods are data-driven and relying on manual annotations. However, because few meteorological observations and buoys over the sea can be realized, obtaining visibility information to help the annotations is difficult. Considering the feasibility of obtaining abundant visible information over the land and the similarity between land fog and sea fog, we propose an unsupervised domain adaptation method to bridge the abundant labeled land fog data and the unlabeled sea fog data to realize the sea fog detection. We used a seeded region growing module to obtain pixel-level masks from rough-labels generated by the unsupervised domain adaptation model. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed method achieves an accuracy of sea fog recognition up to 99.17%, which is nearly 3% higher than those vanilla methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Correlation Context-Driven Method for Sea Fog Detection in Meteorological Satellite Imagery</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/a-correlation-context-driven-method-for-sea-fog-detection-in-meteorological-satellite-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/a-correlation-context-driven-method-for-sea-fog-detection-in-meteorological-satellite-imagery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sea fog detection is a challenging and essential issue in satellite remote sensing. Although conventional threshold methods and deep learning methods can achieve pixel-level classification, it is difficult to distinguish ambiguous boundaries and thin structures from the background. Considering the correlations between neighbor pixels and the affinities between superpixels, a correlation context-driven method for sea fog detection is proposed in this letter, which mainly consists of a two-stage superpixel-based fully convolutional network (SFCNet), named SFCNet. A fully connected Conditional Random Field (CRF) is utilized to model the dependencies between pixels. To alleviate the problem of high cloud occlusion, an attentive Generative Adversarial Network (GAN) is implemented for image enhancement by exploiting contextual information. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed method achieves 91.65% mIoU and obtains more refined segmentation results, performing well in detecting fogs in small, broken bits and weak contrast thin structures, as well as detects more obscured parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
