<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paper-conference | BUPT-PRIS-727</title>
    <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication-type/paper-conference/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication-type/paper-conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>paper-conference</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/media/icon_huf3e0a2e529153e638e98ead8993d51a7_215518_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>paper-conference</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication-type/paper-conference/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather2K: A Multivariate Spatio-Temporal Benchmark Dataset for Meteorological Forecasting Based on Real-Time Observation Data from Ground Weather Stations</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/weather2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/weather2k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weather forecasting is one of the cornerstones of meteorological work. In this paper, we present a new benchmark dataset named Weather2K, which aims to make up for the deficiencies of existing weather forecasting datasets in terms of real-time, reliability, and diversity, as well as the key bottleneck of data quality. To be specific, our Weather2K is featured from the following aspects: 1) Reliable and real-time data. The data is hourly collected from 2,130 ground weather stations covering an area of 6 million square kilometers. 2) Multivariate meteorological variables. 20 meteorological factors and 3 constants for position information are provided with a length of 40,896 time steps. 3) Applicable to diverse tasks. We conduct a set of baseline tests on time series forecasting and spatio-temporal forecasting. To the best of our knowledge, our Weather2K is the first attempt to tackle weather forecasting task by taking full advantage of the strengths of observation data from ground weather stations. Based on Weather2K, we further propose Meteorological Factors based Multi-Graph Convolution Network (MFMGCN), which can effectively construct the intrinsic correlation among geographic locations based on meteorological factors. Sufficient experiments show that MFMGCN improves both the forecasting performance and temporal robustness. We hope our Weather2K can significantly motivate researchers to develop efficient and accurate algorithms to advance the task of weather forecasting. The dataset can be available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bycnfz/weather2k/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bycnfz/weather2k/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention based Long Short-Term Memory Network for Coastal Visibility Forecast</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/attention-based-long-short-term-memory-network-for-coastal-visibility-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/attention-based-long-short-term-memory-network-for-coastal-visibility-forecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visibility prediction in coastal areas has always been an important issue affecting the safety of residents and the efficiency of urban transportation. The visibility prediction methods currently used by meteorological centers are mainly based on the statistical forecast with relatively low prediction accuracy and high computational complexity. These methods cannot work well with large amounts of data. However, with the rapid development of deep learning technology, the use of deep learning has become a primary trend. In this paper, we propose our visibility prediction model based on (Long Short-Term Memory) LSTM network and self-attention mechanism. The model takes Medium-range Forecasts Data from European Centre for Mediumrange Weather Forecasting (ECMWF) which we use EC data to refer it for simplicity and observatory visibility data as input to predict and uses the LSTM network as the backbone to extract time series information. We also use self-attention mechanism to process the input data before the data is input to the model to let the model better focus on the valuable information for prediction. Compared with the predicted visibility in EC data, our proposed method improved the 3-hour prediction accuracy by 20%, 1.5 times, and 8 times for high-range, medium-range, and low-range visibility, respectively. We also find the data imbalance will greatly affect the prediction accuracy for low-visibility data and use the weighted-loss and mix-up data augmentation strategy model in our model training. We improved the accuracy of low-visibility data by 1.2 times while the prediction results of high-visibility and medium-visibility data remained almost the same. In addition, we conduct several experiments to verify the effectiveness of our model design and the rationality of data augmentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating Only at Definite Pixels- A Novel Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation Method for Sea Fog Recognition</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/annotating-only-at-definite-pixels-a-novel-weakly-supervised-semantic-segmentation-method-for-sea-fog-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/annotating-only-at-definite-pixels-a-novel-weakly-supervised-semantic-segmentation-method-for-sea-fog-recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sea fog recognition is a challenging and significant semantic segmentation task in remote sensing images. The fully supervised learning method relies on the pixel-level label, which is labor-intensive and time-consuming. Moreover, it is impossible to accurately annotate all pixels of the sea fog region due to the limited ability of the human eye to distinguish between low clouds and sea fog. In this paper, we propose a novel approach of point-based annotation for weakly supervised semantic segmentation with the auxiliary information of International Comprehensive Ocean-Atmosphere Data Set (ICOADS) visibility data. It only needs several definite points for both foreground and background, which significantly reduces the annotation cost of manpower. We conduct extensive experiments on Himawari-8 satellite remote sensing images to demonstrate the effectiveness of our annotation method. The mean intersection over union (mIoU) and overall recognition accuracy of our annotation method reach 82.72% and 95.18 %, respectively. Compared with the fully supervised learning method, the accuracy and the recognition rate of sea fog area are improved with a maximum increase of 7.69% and 9.69 %, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify, Guess and Reconstruct- Three Principles for Cloud Removal Task</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/identify-guess-and-reconstruct-three-principles-for-cloud-removal-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/identify-guess-and-reconstruct-three-principles-for-cloud-removal-task/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote sensing images serve a significant role in earth observation to tackle climate change and post-disaster reconstruction concerns. However, optical images are obscured by clouds or haze, preventing precise earth observation; hence, cloud removal has been a hot topic among concerned scholars. The objective of this article is to make cloud removal more efficient and explicable by proposing three principles: identifying clouds, guessing objects beneath the clouds, and reconstructing the cloudy area. In addition, a modified dual contrastive learning Generative Adversarial Network is proposed based on these three principles by adding cloud detection and weight sharing strategy to obtain cloud semantics. In particular, we align two datasets by forming a quaternary sample pair that includes not only optical pictures and SAR images, but also region information for a more precise reconstruction. Our experiment results on the integrated dataset reveal the superiority of proposed method over previous cloud removal methods and the effectiveness of added modules through ablation experiments, with PSNR and SSIM values of 26.2 and 0.728, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
