<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ziheng Yang | BUPT-PRIS-727</title>
    <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/authors/ziheng-yang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/authors/ziheng-yang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ziheng Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/media/icon_huf3e0a2e529153e638e98ead8993d51a7_215518_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Ziheng Yang</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/authors/ziheng-yang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoANet: A Motion Attention Network for Sea Fog Detection in Time Series Meteorological Satellite Imagery</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/moanet-a-motion-attention-network-for-sea-fog-detection-in-time-series-meteorological-satellite-imagery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/moanet-a-motion-attention-network-for-sea-fog-detection-in-time-series-meteorological-satellite-imagery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sea fog detection is a significant and challenging issue in meteorological satellite imagery. Distinguishing between sea fog and low clouds is challenging due to the similar morphology and brightness characteristics of these two phenomena on the imageries. Most of the existing deep learning methods are based on a single imagery feature extraction without the time-related features in imagery sequence. Although the designed temporal models, such as temporal U-Net, expand the available features from a single imagery to the consecutive frames and introduce general temporal information, the learned motion features are not explicit and can only be implicitly learned through a large amount of data. Thus, we introduce motion features obtained from continuous temporal imagery sequences into the sea fog detection task due to the discrepancy between sea fog and other types of clouds. In this article, under the motion features acquired by Horn–Schunck (HS) optical flow method and attention mechanisms, a Motion Attention Network (MoANet) for sea fog detection is proposed, named MoANet. We performed detailed experiments on the Himawaria-8 satellite imagery data set (H-8 Dataset). The Mean Intersection over Union (MIoU) of our method reaches 81.38%, which is 6.49% higher than the single imagery method. The visualization of the results shows that MoANet has more smooth edges, as well as detects more complete area than others. Furthermore, we validate on International Comprehensive Ocean-Atmosphere Data Set (ICOADS) through contrasting visibility value to prove the practicality of the proposed method and the accuracy achieves 90.65%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather2K: A Multivariate Spatio-Temporal Benchmark Dataset for Meteorological Forecasting Based on Real-Time Observation Data from Ground Weather Stations</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/weather2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publication/weather2k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weather forecasting is one of the cornerstones of meteorological work. In this paper, we present a new benchmark dataset named Weather2K, which aims to make up for the deficiencies of existing weather forecasting datasets in terms of real-time, reliability, and diversity, as well as the key bottleneck of data quality. To be specific, our Weather2K is featured from the following aspects: 1) Reliable and real-time data. The data is hourly collected from 2,130 ground weather stations covering an area of 6 million square kilometers. 2) Multivariate meteorological variables. 20 meteorological factors and 3 constants for position information are provided with a length of 40,896 time steps. 3) Applicable to diverse tasks. We conduct a set of baseline tests on time series forecasting and spatio-temporal forecasting. To the best of our knowledge, our Weather2K is the first attempt to tackle weather forecasting task by taking full advantage of the strengths of observation data from ground weather stations. Based on Weather2K, we further propose Meteorological Factors based Multi-Graph Convolution Network (MFMGCN), which can effectively construct the intrinsic correlation among geographic locations based on meteorological factors. Sufficient experiments show that MFMGCN improves both the forecasting performance and temporal robustness. We hope our Weather2K can significantly motivate researchers to develop efficient and accurate algorithms to advance the task of weather forecasting. The dataset can be available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bycnfz/weather2k/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bycnfz/weather2k/&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
