<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>unsupervised domain adaptation | BUPT-PRIS-727</title>
    <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/unsupervised-domain-adaptation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/unsupervised-domain-adaptation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>unsupervised domain adaptation</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/media/icon_huf3e0a2e529153e638e98ead8993d51a7_215518_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>unsupervised domain adaptation</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/tag/unsupervised-domain-adaptation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eyes of the Gods: A Survey of Unsupervised Domain Adaptation Methods Based on Remote Sensing Data</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/the-eyes-of-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/the-eyes-of-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of the remote sensing monitoring and computer vision technology, the deep learning method has made a great progress to achieve applications such as earth observation, climate change and even space exploration. However, the model trained on existing data cannot be directly used to handle the new remote sensing data, and labeling the new data is also time-consuming and labor-intensive. Unsupervised Domain Adaptation (UDA) is one of the solutions to the aforementioned problems of labeled data defined as the source domain and unlabeled data as the target domain, i.e., its essential purpose is to obtain a well-trained model and tackle the problem of data distribution discrepancy defined as the domain shift between the source and target domain. There are a lot of reviews that have elaborated on UDA methods based on natural data, but few of these studies take into consideration thorough remote sensing applications and contributions. Thus, in this paper, in order to explore the further progress and development of UDA methods in remote sensing, based on the analysis of the causes of domain shift, a comprehensive review is provided with a fine-grained taxonomy of UDA methods applied for remote sensing data, which includes Generative training, Adversarial training, Self-training and Hybrid training methods, to better assist scholars in understanding remote sensing data and further advance the development of methods. Moreover, remote sensing applications are introduced by a thorough dataset analysis. Meanwhile, we sort out definitions and methodology introductions of partial, open-set and multi-domain UDA, which are more pertinent to real-world remote sensing applications. We can draw the conclusion that UDA methods in the field of remote sensing data are carried out later than those applied in natural images, and due to the domain gap caused by appearance differences, most of methods focus on how to use generative training (GT) methods to improve the model’s performance. Finally, we describe the potential deficiencies and further in-depth insights of UDA in the field of remote sensing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Adaptation on Multiple Cloud Recognition From Different Types of Meteorological Satellite</title>
      <link>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/domain-adaptation-on-multiple-cloud-recognition-from-different-types-of-meteorological-satellite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BUPT-PRIS-727.github.io/publications/domain-adaptation-on-multiple-cloud-recognition-from-different-types-of-meteorological-satellite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meteorological satellites have become an indispensable meteorological tool for earth observation, as aiding in areas such as cloud detection, which has important guiding significance for maritime activities. However, it is time-consuming and labor-intensive to obtain fine-grained annotations provided by artificial experience or mature satellite cloud products for multi-spectral maritime cloud imageries, especially when new satellites are launched. Moreover, due to the data discrepancy caused by different detection bands, existing models have inadequate generalization performance compared to new satellites, and some cannot be directly migrated. In this paper, to reduce the data distribution’s discrepancy, an approach is presented based on unsupervised domain adaption method for marine cloud detection task based on Himawari-8 satellite data as a source domain and Fengyun-4 satellite data as a target domain. The goal of the proposed method is to leverage the representation power of adversarial learning to extract domain-invariant features, consisting of a segmentation model, a feature extract model for target domain, and a domain discriminator. In addition, aiming to remedy the discrepancy of detection bands, a band mapping module is designed to implement consistency between different bands. The result of the experiments demonstrated the effectiveness of the proposed method with a 7% improvement compared with the comparative experiment. We also designed a series of statistical experiments on different satellite data to further study cloudy perception representation, including data visualization experiment and cloud type statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
